<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-07T16:04:22-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chad Underwood</title><subtitle>Personal site of Chad Underwood. Chad Underwood is a Systems Anaylst who specializes in Process Improvement.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How To Easily Generate Favicons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Easily-Generate-Favicons/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Easily Generate Favicons" /><published>2020-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Easily-Generate-Favicons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Easily-Generate-Favicons/">&lt;p&gt;Easy to generate Favicons for everything at once. I came across this website &lt;a href=&quot;https://realfavicongenerator.net/&quot;&gt;Real Favicon Generator&lt;/a&gt;. This allowed me to take my logo and upload it&lt;!--more--&gt; and then it did the lifting. I was prompted for some choices on how I wanted things to look. Next all I needed to do was click submit. Then I could download the results, which included a zip file of icons and the code to be input into the head of my site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="favicon," /><category term="logo," /><category term="html" /><summary type="html">Easy to generate Favicons for everything at once. I came across this website Real Favicon Generator. This allowed me to take my logo and upload it</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Manage Branches In GitHub</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-to-Manage-Branches-In-GitHub/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Manage Branches In GitHub" /><published>2020-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-to-Manage-Branches-In-GitHub</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-to-Manage-Branches-In-GitHub/">&lt;p&gt;I finally got to a point where I need to manage 2 sets of code&lt;!--more--&gt; for my personal website page. I created my Dev environment today so I can work on new features without taking a chance on destroying my currently working code. In theory, I understood why you run 2 code sets but now that I’ve seen the branches in action it makes more sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I had to do was create a second branch. This brought over my production code. From there all I needed to do was write new code and test it worked. Once I verified it was working, then I had to pull it into production. Easy, peasy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="github," /><category term="branches" /><summary type="html">I finally got to a point where I need to manage 2 sets of code</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Off and On</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Off-And-On/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Off and On" /><published>2020-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Off-And-On</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Off-And-On/">&lt;p&gt;This journey started in High School. I knew I was going to work in tech.&lt;!--more--&gt; Tech was the one passion I have always had, specifically computers. I had taken every single computer class I could. Then came my senior year and Advanced MIS. I always excelled in MIS. I passed everything with 100%. Then came my final assignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I had to do was build an application in VB (Visual basic for you young cats). I decided that I was going to make a black jack game. It seemed like it would use everything that we had learned in the class that year. We had 6 weeks to get it working. On the last day of the class, Chad’s version of Black Jack didn’t work. It was that day, I knew coding was not for me and I said I would never try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have seen people post their personal portfolio websites and I knew I had to have one. I have wanted my own space where I fully owned my data. A site, unlike social media, where I control everything. The truth is I have had an idea of what I wanted my site to look like. I have searched to the end of the web and back to find a theme that would fit all the little details. So I decided to restart on my coding journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://freecodecamp.org&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;. Their site makes learning the basics of HTML and CSS easy. They walk you through learning bits and pieces at a time and it was easy for me. I was on the track to learning as quickly and as much as I could. Amazingly, one of the projects there is to create a personal portfolio site. I  was able to complete almost all of the content they were offering for a Front-End developer certificate. Then I was distracted by the blessing of a new child and life. So back off the track I went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-ahead&quot;&gt;Moving Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward, to this year (2020), we are once again expecting a new child. My wife has decided to go back to school and I needed something to fill my extra time. I still have the itch to create that personal website. I went back to freecodecamp.org and rushed through all of the tutorials once again to refresh. So now I am back on track and motivated more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What has made this time different than the others? I  found a great community on Twitter that motivates me. They are mostly experienced developers preaching the gospel of development. By preaching I mean, they let newer developers know the truth about development. They cut through the self depreciating thoughts, that you don’t know enough to be a compentent developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be known, I already knew this about tech; but failed to realize it about development. I always just assumed every developer knew most everything, about a language, before they started really doing development. Personally, I have been in the tech field for 13 years and I got my start by Googling everything. Now that I am more seasoned, I don’t have to Google as much but a search engine is my best friend. However, I found that a lot of the senior developers are just Googlers with experience; just like me. This made learning to code seem easier and obtainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-i-am-now&quot;&gt;Where I Am Now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over these months, I have been working to take in little by litte. The difference, this time, has been knowing that I need to be steady and learn when I can. The fact, I don’t have to know everything just puts me at ease. Cramming has never been my strong suit because I tend to burn out fast (and it seems others do too)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past 3 months, I have been able to retain more than I ever have before and it all is just starting to make sense. In the past, things never seemed to connect. I could make things happen but nothing like now. I am actually releasing my site to the world and it is &lt;strong&gt;EXCITING!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a few projects lined out that should continue raise my confidence level. These projects will allow me to continue to learn new things but with deadlines involved, just like a developer would. It is exciting to know, this time, I stand a chance to make it! For those in #100daysofcode, you will make it too, if you stick with it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="myjourney," /><summary type="html">This journey started in High School. I knew I was going to work in tech.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll-Config-YAML</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-Jekyll-Config-yaml/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll-Config-YAML" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-Jekyll-Config-yaml</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-Jekyll-Config-yaml/">&lt;p&gt;YAML is the configuration settings of a Jekyll site. You can setup custom fields to setup easy to change settings.&lt;!--more--&gt; This works great for things like social media names or things that are hard to remember but need to be referred to a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll," /><summary type="html">YAML is the configuration settings of a Jekyll site. You can setup custom fields to setup easy to change settings.</summary></entry></feed>