<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-22T13:59:59-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chad Underwood</title><subtitle>Merging life, technology, and business for your prosperity.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Knowing Your Twitter Audience Personally</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/knowing-your-twitter-audience-personally/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Knowing Your Twitter Audience Personally" /><published>2020-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-10-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/knowing-your-twitter-audience-personally</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/knowing-your-twitter-audience-personally/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;old-idea-in-a-new-context&quot;&gt;Old idea in a new context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personas are not new. They are used in UX design. Companies use them to define their customers and their experience. Personas will work for small and large accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow along. I’ll explain how and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personas are made up people. Each persona represents a portion of your target audience. Personas create empathy for your audience. And defines the experience they want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create 3 made up people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each made up person is a persona.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give each persona a name and a face.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t use&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;people you know&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;celebrities
&lt;em&gt;(This creates bias towards these people’s personalities.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Define each of the persona’s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;interests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pain points&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Define these traits through research you do and feedback you receive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take into account&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what you want to tweet about&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;success of previous tweets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;feedback in the DMs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;comments in tweets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;personas-evolve&quot;&gt;Personas evolve&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As data changes, your personas should evolve. From this evolution you need to adapt your account. This will keep your audience fully engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-a-basic-persona-looks-like&quot;&gt;What A Basic Persona Looks Like.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is an example Persona&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Larry Wharton&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Needs:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;sales funnel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;email newsletter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;negative talk&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;politics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interests/Loves&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;gumroad&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;growing business&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;steak&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;eggs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;dividends&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;more-about-larry&quot;&gt;More about Larry…&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Larry is the main audience. You know what content keeps Larry happy.  Avoid politics and negativity. Post content to his loves and interests. This info gives 7 topics to keep him engaged. Larry is the largest part of your following. Tweet to his interests the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-about-the-other-guy&quot;&gt;What about the other guy?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other personas are smaller parts of the audience. There will be overlap into Larry’s characteristics. The overlap is your bread and butter. The overlap will be your most engaged with tweets. As you adapt your personas, you will see your following and engagement increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content should be directed to the smaller portion of your audience, too. Expect this content to be engaged with the least. But this content keeps the smaller parts happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-the-future&quot;&gt;For the future.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personas define your future content. Done correctly you will increase engagement. It is a small task to know exactly who is in the crowd. They key is posting to the overlapping topics between all of the audience the most.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="UX" /><category term="Design," /><category term="twitter," /><category term="social" /><category term="networking," /><category term="social," /><category term="personas" /><summary type="html">Old idea in a new context Personas are not new. They are used in UX design. Companies use them to define their customers and their experience. Personas will work for small and large accounts. Follow along. I’ll explain how and why. Personas are made up people. Each persona represents a portion of your target audience. Personas create empathy for your audience. And defines the experience they want. Getting Started Create 3 made up people. Each made up person is a persona. Give each persona a name and a face. Don’t use people you know celebrities (This creates bias towards these people’s personalities.) Next Steps Define each of the persona’s interests pain points wants needs Define these traits through research you do and feedback you receive. Take into account what you want to tweet about success of previous tweets feedback in the DMs comments in tweets Personas evolve As data changes, your personas should evolve. From this evolution you need to adapt your account. This will keep your audience fully engaged. What A Basic Persona Looks Like. Here is an example Persona Name: Larry Wharton Needs: sales funnel Wants email newsletter Hates negative talk politics Interests/Loves gumroad growing business steak eggs dividends More about Larry… Larry is the main audience. You know what content keeps Larry happy. Avoid politics and negativity. Post content to his loves and interests. This info gives 7 topics to keep him engaged. Larry is the largest part of your following. Tweet to his interests the most. What about the other guy? The other personas are smaller parts of the audience. There will be overlap into Larry’s characteristics. The overlap is your bread and butter. The overlap will be your most engaged with tweets. As you adapt your personas, you will see your following and engagement increase. Content should be directed to the smaller portion of your audience, too. Expect this content to be engaged with the least. But this content keeps the smaller parts happy. For the future. Personas define your future content. Done correctly you will increase engagement. It is a small task to know exactly who is in the crowd. They key is posting to the overlapping topics between all of the audience the most.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Things Not To Do On Twitter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/5-things-not-to-do-on-twitter/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Things Not To Do On Twitter" /><published>2020-09-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/5-things-not-to-do-on-twitter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/5-things-not-to-do-on-twitter/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are rules to the Twitter community. There is &lt;a href=&quot;https://chadunderwood.com/article/5-tips-to-grow-as-new-twitter-user/&quot;&gt;things you can do to grow.&lt;/a&gt; Also, there are things you can do to decline. After reading this you have no excuses to decline. Consider this your warning. You will end up blocked by most accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these individually, are enough for you to lose your following. All of that hard work will be gone. And it will be gone overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t ask for follow backs&lt;/strong&gt;
 When you are a smaller it seems hard to grow. You are willing to do 	anything to get a follow. Including, getting in the DMs and asking for follows. Larger accounts see these all the time. The larger accounts will not be empathetic to your situation. Most likely, they will just block you.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Access to their tweets is more important than having them as a follower. One retweet from a large account can amass many followers. If you are on their radar enough they will follow you on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The better play is to quote tweet their tweets. They get a notification you are adding value to their tweet and you are helping spread their name. Its a win win. You give more to your followers and you are noticed by the larger account. Keep getting their attention and they will follow you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t promote on other people’s tweet&lt;/strong&gt;
 Promotion on other’s tweets is another huge no no. Selling is something that has to be done correctly. Spamming everywhere just doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Most accounts are working a plan to push an offer to their followers. You dropping a link in their comments, is throwing that plan off. Its the equivalent of walking into a grocery store and trying to sell someone your milk brand. The store would kick you out instantly and the Twitter account will block you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t expect immediate responses in DMs&lt;/strong&gt;
 One of the greatest things about the openness of Twitter is the direct messages. You can directly contact with much larger accounts. Most large accounts are willing to share help and advice. This advice and help can be invaluable. Think about this before pressing for a response.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Most small accounts fail to think about the person behind the large account. If they have 10,000 followers, they probably have a lot of unanswered DMs. Of the bigger accounts I know, they all try to respond to all DMs. Just realize it takes a lot of time. Pressing for a response, will stop you from getting a response and land you on the blocked list.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t follow then unfollow&lt;/strong&gt;
 Follow then unfollow is done by sleazy accounts. They follow as many accounts as possible hoping the person will follow them back. This method can help you get more followers. However, there is a huge drawback.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This type of following will not help you. You need a following that will  reply and engage on your posts. Accounts who follow everyone aren’t engaged. If you only want a number, this way might work for you. If you are looking to make money, this method will never get followers that pay. Brands don’t invest in accounts with no engagement. Larger accounts seeing follow then unfollow will block you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t post quotes without the source&lt;/strong&gt;
 Posting quotes is no big deal. You must make sure you are listing your source. People are happy that you shared a good quote. They don’t care if you wrote it or not. There could be value for them just by knowing where the quote came from.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Posting quotes without your source is considered piracy. You will be publicly called out. Once publicly outed, you can guarantee you will be blocked. People don’t like thieves and don’t want to be associated with thieves. You will watch your follower account drop.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Tip&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;Don’t engage with trolls&lt;/strong&gt;
 This one is for your own sanity. If you find yourself engaging a troll, you will end up frustrated and angry. Trolls will do anything to make you unhappy. Their only goal is for you to publicly lose your temper. It is best to just block them and forget they exist.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ending up blocked by a bunch of accounts will make growth impossible. Don’t get caught in these traps. Instead follow these tips, you won’t have any problems on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="social" /><category term="networking," /><category term="Twitter" /><summary type="html">There are rules to the Twitter community. There is things you can do to grow. Also, there are things you can do to decline. After reading this you have no excuses to decline. Consider this your warning. You will end up blocked by most accounts. All of these individually, are enough for you to lose your following. All of that hard work will be gone. And it will be gone overnight. Don’t ask for follow backs When you are a smaller it seems hard to grow. You are willing to do anything to get a follow. Including, getting in the DMs and asking for follows. Larger accounts see these all the time. The larger accounts will not be empathetic to your situation. Most likely, they will just block you. Access to their tweets is more important than having them as a follower. One retweet from a large account can amass many followers. If you are on their radar enough they will follow you on their own. The better play is to quote tweet their tweets. They get a notification you are adding value to their tweet and you are helping spread their name. Its a win win. You give more to your followers and you are noticed by the larger account. Keep getting their attention and they will follow you. Don’t promote on other people’s tweet Promotion on other’s tweets is another huge no no. Selling is something that has to be done correctly. Spamming everywhere just doesn’t work. Most accounts are working a plan to push an offer to their followers. You dropping a link in their comments, is throwing that plan off. Its the equivalent of walking into a grocery store and trying to sell someone your milk brand. The store would kick you out instantly and the Twitter account will block you. Don’t expect immediate responses in DMs One of the greatest things about the openness of Twitter is the direct messages. You can directly contact with much larger accounts. Most large accounts are willing to share help and advice. This advice and help can be invaluable. Think about this before pressing for a response. Most small accounts fail to think about the person behind the large account. If they have 10,000 followers, they probably have a lot of unanswered DMs. Of the bigger accounts I know, they all try to respond to all DMs. Just realize it takes a lot of time. Pressing for a response, will stop you from getting a response and land you on the blocked list. Don’t follow then unfollow Follow then unfollow is done by sleazy accounts. They follow as many accounts as possible hoping the person will follow them back. This method can help you get more followers. However, there is a huge drawback. This type of following will not help you. You need a following that will reply and engage on your posts. Accounts who follow everyone aren’t engaged. If you only want a number, this way might work for you. If you are looking to make money, this method will never get followers that pay. Brands don’t invest in accounts with no engagement. Larger accounts seeing follow then unfollow will block you. Don’t post quotes without the source Posting quotes is no big deal. You must make sure you are listing your source. People are happy that you shared a good quote. They don’t care if you wrote it or not. There could be value for them just by knowing where the quote came from. Posting quotes without your source is considered piracy. You will be publicly called out. Once publicly outed, you can guarantee you will be blocked. People don’t like thieves and don’t want to be associated with thieves. You will watch your follower account drop. Bonus Tip - Don’t engage with trolls This one is for your own sanity. If you find yourself engaging a troll, you will end up frustrated and angry. Trolls will do anything to make you unhappy. Their only goal is for you to publicly lose your temper. It is best to just block them and forget they exist. Ending up blocked by a bunch of accounts will make growth impossible. Don’t get caught in these traps. Instead follow these tips, you won’t have any problems on Twitter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Tips To Grow As New Twitter User</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/5-tips-to-grow-as-new-twitter-user/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Tips To Grow As New Twitter User" /><published>2020-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/5-tips-to-grow-as-new-twitter-user</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/5-tips-to-grow-as-new-twitter-user/">&lt;p&gt;You signed up for a Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you followed some great people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do now? Great that you ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pick 2-3 Topics to Tweet About&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Before you start tweeting, you should know your topics you will tweet about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be your niche. You niche will set you apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your first topic should be something you can talk about for 30 minutes without stopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2nd and 3rd topics are not as important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But they should compliment the 1st one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many topics and people are less likely to follow you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Add value to larger accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Engaging with others posts is where things will start to flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helps other users see your profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other users will start seeing your comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then eventually follow you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post 3 times daily&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It is necessary to post daily before growth will start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone comes to your profile, they need to see what you are about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 posts per day is all you need. Remember to stay on topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retweet 5-10 times per day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Retweets add content to your page you didn’t come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They allow you to push more value to your followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good amount is 5 - 10 daily. Make sure they are spread out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to push to many tweets at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quote Tweet 3 times per day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Quote tweets are another great way to have content with little thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All you have to do is retweet and then add you spin to the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be an extension of their thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or a differing opinion. Completely up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Tip: Schedule Tweets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Since, I like you. I’m adding another tip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scheduling tweets is the best way post 3 tweets daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some days you’ll have a ton of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some you won’t. For the days you don’t scheduling will save you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tools to help schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twitter has one built in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is one called Tweetdeck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally I use (affilliate link) &lt;a href=&quot;https://hypefury.com/?via=chadaunderwood&quot;&gt;Hypefury&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HypeFury allows me to schedule and automatically retweet on a schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link above will get you a free trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you try it out, you won’t use anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the tips above and you will start to see growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more you practice the better you will get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to learn how to craft engaging tweets?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use the guide that I used. (affiliate link)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/2PSFLo8&quot;&gt;Get the World Talking - Mastering Twitter Engagement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the tips in this guide will help you become a master in engagement.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="twitter," /><category term="social" /><category term="networking" /><summary type="html">You signed up for a Twitter account. Then you followed some great people. What do you do now? Great that you ask. Let’s get started. Pick 2-3 Topics to Tweet About Before you start tweeting, you should know your topics you will tweet about. This will be your niche. You niche will set you apart. Your first topic should be something you can talk about for 30 minutes without stopping. The 2nd and 3rd topics are not as important. But they should compliment the 1st one. Too many topics and people are less likely to follow you. Add value to larger accounts Engaging with others posts is where things will start to flow. This helps other users see your profile. Other users will start seeing your comments. Then eventually follow you. Post 3 times daily It is necessary to post daily before growth will start. When someone comes to your profile, they need to see what you are about. 3 posts per day is all you need. Remember to stay on topic. Retweet 5-10 times per day Retweets add content to your page you didn’t come up with. They allow you to push more value to your followers. A good amount is 5 - 10 daily. Make sure they are spread out. You don’t want to push to many tweets at once. Quote Tweet 3 times per day Quote tweets are another great way to have content with little thought. All you have to do is retweet and then add you spin to the post. This can be an extension of their thought. Or a differing opinion. Completely up to you. Bonus Tip: Schedule Tweets Since, I like you. I’m adding another tip. Scheduling tweets is the best way post 3 tweets daily. Some days you’ll have a ton of ideas. Some you won’t. For the days you don’t scheduling will save you. There are tools to help schedule. Twitter has one built in. And there is one called Tweetdeck. Personally I use (affilliate link) Hypefury. HypeFury allows me to schedule and automatically retweet on a schedule. The link above will get you a free trial. Once you try it out, you won’t use anything else. Conclusion Follow the tips above and you will start to see growth. The more you practice the better you will get. Want to learn how to craft engaging tweets? Use the guide that I used. (affiliate link) Get the World Talking - Mastering Twitter Engagement Using the tips in this guide will help you become a master in engagement.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How We Deal With Change</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/How-We-Deal-With-Change/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How We Deal With Change" /><published>2020-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/How-We-Deal-With-Change</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/How-We-Deal-With-Change/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/7emotionsofchange.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;7 Emotions of Change&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Alexas Fotos from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When dealing with change and people, you have to realize there are emotions tied to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All humans must go through certain emotions during change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is important because you need to know how to deal with people during change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These apply when you are changing your life or if something happens to someone you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will have to go through these stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its easier to deal with the emotions, if you know what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 7 emotions that occur before acceptance of a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-7-stages&quot;&gt;The 7 stages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People progress through all 7 in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Shock&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Disbelief&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Self Doubt&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Acceptance&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Experimentation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Search for Meaning&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each individual may vary how long  they spend in each stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are emotions so some people are better equipped to deal with stressful situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-1---shock&quot;&gt;Stage 1 - Shock&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a person is shock they will be numb to the news of the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They expect one thing but reality is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-2---denial&quot;&gt;Stage 2 - Denial&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second stage, people deny the changes are happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will carry on as if nothing has happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-3---self-doubt&quot;&gt;Stage 3 - Self Doubt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality sets in.  Frustration begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People can become angry or even depressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These people you need to help see the positives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must show the most empathy towards people in doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People generally spend the most time here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-4---acceptance&quot;&gt;Stage 4 - Acceptance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acceptance is where you want to get people quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get them here by showing great empathy and showing them the greener grass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people that get here the quickest can help the ones that are in the 1st 3 stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-5---experimentation&quot;&gt;Stage 5 - Experimentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People here will have a new energy and positive attitude towards the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The change starts setting in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-6---search-for-meaning&quot;&gt;Stage 6 - Search for Meaning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the change actually becomes real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People want to know what happened and why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the questions occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stage-7---integration&quot;&gt;Stage 7 - Integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the new attitudes and behaviors become habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could also be called acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know the stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can probably see situations where you went through the stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing this is important to all coaches, trainers, and leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are more effective if you understand, what your people are going through.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="process" /><category term="improvement," /><category term="change," /><summary type="html">Photo by Alexas Fotos from Pexels When dealing with change and people, you have to realize there are emotions tied to change. All humans must go through certain emotions during change. This is important because you need to know how to deal with people during change. These apply when you are changing your life or if something happens to someone you know. They will have to go through these stages. Its easier to deal with the emotions, if you know what to expect. Let’s get started. There are 7 emotions that occur before acceptance of a change. The 7 stages People progress through all 7 in order. Shock Disbelief Self Doubt Acceptance Experimentation Search for Meaning Integration Each individual may vary how long they spend in each stage. These are emotions so some people are better equipped to deal with stressful situations. Stage 1 - Shock When a person is shock they will be numb to the news of the change. They expect one thing but reality is different. Stage 2 - Denial In the second stage, people deny the changes are happening. They will carry on as if nothing has happened. Stage 3 - Self Doubt Reality sets in. Frustration begins. People can become angry or even depressed. These people you need to help see the positives. You must show the most empathy towards people in doubt. People generally spend the most time here. Stage 4 - Acceptance Acceptance is where you want to get people quickly. You get them here by showing great empathy and showing them the greener grass. The people that get here the quickest can help the ones that are in the 1st 3 stages. Stage 5 - Experimentation People here will have a new energy and positive attitude towards the change. The change starts setting in. Stage 6 - Search for Meaning This is where the change actually becomes real. People want to know what happened and why. This is where the questions occur. Stage 7 - Integration This is where the new attitudes and behaviors become habits. This could also be called acceptance. Now that you know the stages. You can probably see situations where you went through the stages. Knowing this is important to all coaches, trainers, and leaders. You are more effective if you understand, what your people are going through.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/7emotionsofchange.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/7emotionsofchange.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s All My Fault</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/Its-All-My-Fault/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It’s All My Fault" /><published>2020-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/Its-All-My-Fault</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/Its-All-My-Fault/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/allmyfault.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;All My Fault&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Andrea Piacquadio from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a manager that I would constantly butt heads with. He was military minded. I never seemed to have the right answer for him. I would explain to him endlessly. 
Truth be told, no one cared for him. All for the same reasons. Everyone said “He just doesn’t care to listen.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-top-performer&quot;&gt;The Top Performer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time I was the top performer on our team and top 5% in our department. This is where you wanted to be in the rankings. He brought me into a meeting to let me know that I had a laundry list of things to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After he was done, I was so angry with him that I really didn’t want to talk to him.  I ended up saying, “Yes sir, I’ll fix it.” The tension in the room instantly dropped on his side. I could tell I had made a stride on dealing with his unwillingness to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;explanations-are-just-another-excuse&quot;&gt;Explanations are just another excuse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I ended up learning about him would later, help me change my life. He didn’t want excuses. He took my explaining as excuses. He didn’t care, why it happened. He only wanted assurance, the problem would be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;controlling-the-situation&quot;&gt;Controlling the situation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in life, I figured out this was called taking accountability. Taking accountability allows you to do 3 things. You stop arguments, blaming other people and control the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is being able to control your emotions. Emotions come from things, we feel, we can’t control. If you can stop the trigger of the emotions, you can move on quicker. Accountability is a sure fire way to control most of the emotions you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-accountability-look-like&quot;&gt;What does accountability look like?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem:&lt;/strong&gt;  My kid made bad grades.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The excuse:&lt;/strong&gt; They should’ve worked harder to get a better grade.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability:&lt;/strong&gt; I should’ve spent more time making sure they received the help they needed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;h4 id=&quot;heres-another-example&quot;&gt;Here’s another example.&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem:&lt;/strong&gt; My spouse doesn’t clean the house the way I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The excuse:&lt;/strong&gt; My spouse is just lazy and half way does everything.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability:&lt;/strong&gt; I could’ve gotten up and helped to clean up the mess.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-part-of-the-problem&quot;&gt;Be part of the problem.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see a pattern? Your excuses are what someone else could’ve done. The excuse could be 100% true. With accountability, you’ve got skin in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By taking accountability, you are now part of the problem. Being part of the problem, changes excuses into something you can control. Controlling the situation, gives you a freedom to fix any problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;out-of-control&quot;&gt;Out of control&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somethings in life that you can’t control. For things you can’t control, learn to let them go. Learn to say, I can’t control this. After you say, “I can’t control it.”, move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You waste so much of your time on things you can’t control. You should take this wasted time and turn it into something productive. Instead invest this new energy into learning a hobby, side venture, or complete a goal you have been putting off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn to become accountable to everything around you. Then learn to let go of things you can’t control. You will find yourself in a much better place. You will have a clear head and a ton of time for you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="accountability," /><category term="excuses" /><summary type="html">Photo by Andrea Piacquadio from Pexels I had a manager that I would constantly butt heads with. He was military minded. I never seemed to have the right answer for him. I would explain to him endlessly. Truth be told, no one cared for him. All for the same reasons. Everyone said “He just doesn’t care to listen.” The Top Performer At the time I was the top performer on our team and top 5% in our department. This is where you wanted to be in the rankings. He brought me into a meeting to let me know that I had a laundry list of things to improve on. After he was done, I was so angry with him that I really didn’t want to talk to him.  I ended up saying, “Yes sir, I’ll fix it.” The tension in the room instantly dropped on his side. I could tell I had made a stride on dealing with his unwillingness to listen. Explanations are just another excuse What I ended up learning about him would later, help me change my life. He didn’t want excuses. He took my explaining as excuses. He didn’t care, why it happened. He only wanted assurance, the problem would be fixed. Controlling the situation Later in life, I figured out this was called taking accountability. Taking accountability allows you to do 3 things. You stop arguments, blaming other people and control the situation. The result is being able to control your emotions. Emotions come from things, we feel, we can’t control. If you can stop the trigger of the emotions, you can move on quicker. Accountability is a sure fire way to control most of the emotions you feel. What does accountability look like? The problem:  My kid made bad grades. The excuse: They should’ve worked harder to get a better grade. Accountability: I should’ve spent more time making sure they received the help they needed. Here’s another example. The problem: My spouse doesn’t clean the house the way I like it. The excuse: My spouse is just lazy and half way does everything. Accountability: I could’ve gotten up and helped to clean up the mess. Be part of the problem. Do you see a pattern? Your excuses are what someone else could’ve done. The excuse could be 100% true. With accountability, you’ve got skin in the game. By taking accountability, you are now part of the problem. Being part of the problem, changes excuses into something you can control. Controlling the situation, gives you a freedom to fix any problem. Out of control Somethings in life that you can’t control. For things you can’t control, learn to let them go. Learn to say, I can’t control this. After you say, “I can’t control it.”, move on. You waste so much of your time on things you can’t control. You should take this wasted time and turn it into something productive. Instead invest this new energy into learning a hobby, side venture, or complete a goal you have been putting off. Learn to become accountable to everything around you. Then learn to let go of things you can’t control. You will find yourself in a much better place. You will have a clear head and a ton of time for you.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/allmyfault.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/allmyfault.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Worst Enemy is Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/My-Worst-Enemy-is-Me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Worst Enemy is Me" /><published>2020-07-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/My-Worst-Enemy-is-Me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/My-Worst-Enemy-is-Me/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/myworstenemyisme.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Worst Enemy&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Andrea Piacquadio from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my life, I spent my quiet time coming up with ideas. Matter of fact, I have a ton of ideas. For those that know me well, I am a very analytical person.I analyze everything around me, constantly. When you meet me, I am very quiet. I am quiet because I am analyzing everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I hold myself back from speaking. I do this because I don’t want to say something stupid. I lack confidence in social situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-great-procrastinator&quot;&gt;The Great Procrastinator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have one other thing that I hold myself back from, action. I tend to be a procrastinator. I always meet deadlines but scramble to get them done at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend hours analyzing how to do something. I have to know everything before I can get started. I have found, what causes this procrastination for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paralyzed&quot;&gt;Paralyzed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I feel like I know everything about a subject, then comes the what I need to get started. Here’s what those look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need a new camera to start that YouTube channel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need more followers to start that newsletter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can’t post this on Instagram because its not a perfect picture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if someone doesn’t like it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The procrastination is not laziness. My procrastination is from fear of failure. This fear is paralyzing. Especially, for a person that lacks self confidence. I don’t want to be seen as a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comfortable-with-uncomfortable&quot;&gt;Comfortable with uncomfortable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife on the other hand is super confident. I think that confidence is what draws me to her. We are the proverbial yin and yang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She drives me to want more from life. At first, I rejected this because it wasn’t normal to just do something that wasn’t planned out. Now, I have become somewhat comfortable with being uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stuck-on-the-diving-board&quot;&gt;Stuck on the diving board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much reflection here’s what I found. If I just start, the voices, in my head, have no influence over me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I wait until I feel ready, I never get started.  Here’s a good quote I came across from somewhere, “If you wait for the perfect temperature in the pool, you’ll always be left standing on the diving board.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read many biographies of, who I would deem, successful people. I have found these people all have the same trait. They start without knowing the how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful people, start and learn as they go. Then, they surround themselves with people who can teach them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-road-ahead&quot;&gt;The Road Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started to make myself do things. I’m still here. I’m not embarrassed. My failures are learning experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now fail in public more. You didn’t even see they happened. In the grand scheme of things, other people are not paying attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My self confidence is higher than ever. I’m moving forward and excited where this road will take me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you can find more confidence to start. Starting is the most important thing. Once you start, the rest falls in place. You’re not lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed this please tell your friends! (it would seriously mean the world to me)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="change," /><category term="procrastination," /><category term="confidence" /><summary type="html">Photo by Andrea Piacquadio from Pexels Most of my life, I spent my quiet time coming up with ideas. Matter of fact, I have a ton of ideas. For those that know me well, I am a very analytical person.I analyze everything around me, constantly. When you meet me, I am very quiet. I am quiet because I am analyzing everything. Truth be told, I hold myself back from speaking. I do this because I don’t want to say something stupid. I lack confidence in social situations. The Great Procrastinator I have one other thing that I hold myself back from, action. I tend to be a procrastinator. I always meet deadlines but scramble to get them done at the last minute. I spend hours analyzing how to do something. I have to know everything before I can get started. I have found, what causes this procrastination for me. Paralyzed Once I feel like I know everything about a subject, then comes the what I need to get started. Here’s what those look like. I need a new camera to start that YouTube channel. I need more followers to start that newsletter. I can’t post this on Instagram because its not a perfect picture. What if someone doesn’t like it. The procrastination is not laziness. My procrastination is from fear of failure. This fear is paralyzing. Especially, for a person that lacks self confidence. I don’t want to be seen as a failure. Comfortable with uncomfortable My wife on the other hand is super confident. I think that confidence is what draws me to her. We are the proverbial yin and yang. She drives me to want more from life. At first, I rejected this because it wasn’t normal to just do something that wasn’t planned out. Now, I have become somewhat comfortable with being uncomfortable. Stuck on the diving board After much reflection here’s what I found. If I just start, the voices, in my head, have no influence over me. If I wait until I feel ready, I never get started. Here’s a good quote I came across from somewhere, “If you wait for the perfect temperature in the pool, you’ll always be left standing on the diving board.” I have read many biographies of, who I would deem, successful people. I have found these people all have the same trait. They start without knowing the how. Successful people, start and learn as they go. Then, they surround themselves with people who can teach them. The Road Ahead I have started to make myself do things. I’m still here. I’m not embarrassed. My failures are learning experiences. I now fail in public more. You didn’t even see they happened. In the grand scheme of things, other people are not paying attention. My self confidence is higher than ever. I’m moving forward and excited where this road will take me. I hope you can find more confidence to start. Starting is the most important thing. Once you start, the rest falls in place. You’re not lazy. If you enjoyed this please tell your friends! (it would seriously mean the world to me)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/myworstenemyisme.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/myworstenemyisme.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Attitude Needed A Wake Up Call</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/My-Attitude-Needed-A-Wake-Up-Call/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Attitude Needed A Wake Up Call" /><published>2020-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/My-Attitude-Needed-A-Wake-Up-Call</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/My-Attitude-Needed-A-Wake-Up-Call/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/MyAttitudeNeededAWakeUpCall.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Worst Enemy&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Andrew Neel from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 6 a.m. The alarm goes off having to be out the door in 30 minutes to make it to work by 7 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hop out of bed. Run to start some coffee. Jump in the shower. Quickly brush my teeth. Sling on some clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running out the door, I pour the coffee into a travel cup and grab my wallet and keys. Now with no time to spare, zooming down the highway at 90 just hoping there’s no traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit the floor running with only seconds between being on time and being late. Starting everyday on a negative note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably would have a better attitude, by escaping my rush after waking up. There’s got to be a better way, I reflected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have come to believe, it is as easy as setting up a routine. So far, here is what I have found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-1-prep-the-night-before&quot;&gt;Step 1. Prep the night before.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you, like me, already know what you need for the next day. There’s no reason not to have it ready the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the same thing you need everyday. Clothes, a drink, some form of lunch, and a shower. Everything except maybe the shower.
Thibaut @Kpaxs
Your evening routine is about taking the decisions out of your morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to wake up already knowing what you’re going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2-wake-up-earlier&quot;&gt;Step 2. Wake up earlier&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is logical but it leads to the 3rd step. Waking up earlier would give time to gather thoughts and plan out the day. Then find a little peace before the chaos of the day starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just make sure not to procrastinate during this extra time. You will end up back where you started. Set a reminder and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-3-take-time-for-yourself&quot;&gt;Step 3. Take time for yourself&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I am not much of a morning person. Most people need coffee but I need isolation. I find that taking 30 minutes to start the day, I am much more productive and happy. This time gives me a chance to gather myself, my thoughts and prepare for the day ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-i-am-doing&quot;&gt;How I am doing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started to slowly incorporate these things into my day. I find that the days, that I do these things, I tend to be happier and more productive. The days where I skip one of these 3 things, the day is chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you can incorporate these into your routine and you will find similar results or maybe there is something you already do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="attitude," /><category term="routine," /><category term="habits," /><category term="morning" /><summary type="html">Photo by Andrew Neel from Pexels It’s 6 a.m. The alarm goes off having to be out the door in 30 minutes to make it to work by 7 a.m. I hop out of bed. Run to start some coffee. Jump in the shower. Quickly brush my teeth. Sling on some clothes. Running out the door, I pour the coffee into a travel cup and grab my wallet and keys. Now with no time to spare, zooming down the highway at 90 just hoping there’s no traffic. Sound familiar? I hit the floor running with only seconds between being on time and being late. Starting everyday on a negative note. I probably would have a better attitude, by escaping my rush after waking up. There’s got to be a better way, I reflected. I have come to believe, it is as easy as setting up a routine. So far, here is what I have found. Step 1. Prep the night before. If you, like me, already know what you need for the next day. There’s no reason not to have it ready the night before. It’s the same thing you need everyday. Clothes, a drink, some form of lunch, and a shower. Everything except maybe the shower. Thibaut @Kpaxs Your evening routine is about taking the decisions out of your morning. You want to wake up already knowing what you’re going to do. Step 2. Wake up earlier This one is logical but it leads to the 3rd step. Waking up earlier would give time to gather thoughts and plan out the day. Then find a little peace before the chaos of the day starts. Just make sure not to procrastinate during this extra time. You will end up back where you started. Set a reminder and stick to it. Step 3. Take time for yourself For me, I am not much of a morning person. Most people need coffee but I need isolation. I find that taking 30 minutes to start the day, I am much more productive and happy. This time gives me a chance to gather myself, my thoughts and prepare for the day ahead. How I am doing. I have started to slowly incorporate these things into my day. I find that the days, that I do these things, I tend to be happier and more productive. The days where I skip one of these 3 things, the day is chaotic. Maybe you can incorporate these into your routine and you will find similar results or maybe there is something you already do.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/MyAttitudeNeededAWakeUpCall.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/MyAttitudeNeededAWakeUpCall.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kids Have Life Figured Out</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/Kids-Have-Life-Figured-Out/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kids Have Life Figured Out" /><published>2020-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/Kids-Have-Life-Figured-Out</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/Kids-Have-Life-Figured-Out/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/kidshavelifefiguredout.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Super Hero Kid&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Porapak Apichodilok from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day my 3 year old wanted a toy from behind the couch. He kept on and on until I stopped what I was doing to get the toy. Why was he so persistent? He knew that eventually I would give in as long as he was persistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;persistence-gets-you-to-the-finish-line&quot;&gt;Persistence gets you to the finish line.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every thing in life you want to accomplish is the same. Rarely, will you get what you want the first time you ask. You must be persistent to get to what you want out of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persistence is what keeps most people from meeting their goals.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that New Year’s resolutions. You probably failed. Me too. I have failed at every New Year’s resolution I have ever set. Only because my persistence stopped the second week of January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-failed-again-why&quot;&gt;I failed again, why?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my reasoning for that. I always set large goals that are extremely hard to obtain. But I never set a path to get there. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s use weight loss an example. We set goal to lose a 100 pounds this year and say we will start going to the gym. We go that first week 7 times. We get sore and life happens. Before we know it, June has arrived and we haven’t seen a gym since January or lost weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We never defined how to get to the goal. We only said we would lose 100 pounds. This is where smaller (micro and macro) goals come into play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we know our end goal. We have to set smaller goals. These smaller goals help us feel accomplished. The accomplishments are what keeps us persistent in reaching the big goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;smaller-goals-defined&quot;&gt;Smaller goals defined.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A micro goal would be, I am going to lose 10 pounds this month. 10 pounds sounds much easier to get to than 100. Also we have set a smaller timeline. 1 month&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have the end game and the short term. I think we need to set even smaller macro goals. The macro goal would be I’m going to the gym 2 times this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-get-it-started-in-here&quot;&gt;Let’s get it started in here.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the most important thing, schedule it and then do it. Put it on your calendar and push yourself to show up. You will be proud of yourself for just showing up. Showing up will keep you motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next week add another macro goal to the first macro goal you set. This could be I am going to lower my sugar intake this week. So now you’re going to the gym 2 days and watching sugar intake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By setting these smaller (macro) goals, you helping yourself form habits and persistence. These habits are the foundations to reach the bigger goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big picture goals are great. The smaller goals are what gets you to the finish line. Start setting these as soon as possible. You will notice your persistence will increase and you will start hitting your goals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="persistence," /><category term="kids," /><category term="goals" /><summary type="html">Photo by Porapak Apichodilok from Pexels The other day my 3 year old wanted a toy from behind the couch. He kept on and on until I stopped what I was doing to get the toy. Why was he so persistent? He knew that eventually I would give in as long as he was persistent. Persistence gets you to the finish line. Every thing in life you want to accomplish is the same. Rarely, will you get what you want the first time you ask. You must be persistent to get to what you want out of life. Persistence is what keeps most people from meeting their goals. Think about that New Year’s resolutions. You probably failed. Me too. I have failed at every New Year’s resolution I have ever set. Only because my persistence stopped the second week of January. I failed again, why? Here’s my reasoning for that. I always set large goals that are extremely hard to obtain. But I never set a path to get there. Let me explain. Let’s use weight loss an example. We set goal to lose a 100 pounds this year and say we will start going to the gym. We go that first week 7 times. We get sore and life happens. Before we know it, June has arrived and we haven’t seen a gym since January or lost weight. We never defined how to get to the goal. We only said we would lose 100 pounds. This is where smaller (micro and macro) goals come into play. Once we know our end goal. We have to set smaller goals. These smaller goals help us feel accomplished. The accomplishments are what keeps us persistent in reaching the big goal. Smaller goals defined. A micro goal would be, I am going to lose 10 pounds this month. 10 pounds sounds much easier to get to than 100. Also we have set a smaller timeline. 1 month Now we have the end game and the short term. I think we need to set even smaller macro goals. The macro goal would be I’m going to the gym 2 times this week. Let’s get it started in here. Now for the most important thing, schedule it and then do it. Put it on your calendar and push yourself to show up. You will be proud of yourself for just showing up. Showing up will keep you motivated. The next week add another macro goal to the first macro goal you set. This could be I am going to lower my sugar intake this week. So now you’re going to the gym 2 days and watching sugar intake. By setting these smaller (macro) goals, you helping yourself form habits and persistence. These habits are the foundations to reach the bigger goal. Big picture goals are great. The smaller goals are what gets you to the finish line. Start setting these as soon as possible. You will notice your persistence will increase and you will start hitting your goals.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/kidshavelifefiguredout.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/kidshavelifefiguredout.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Decade of Self Reflection</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/Decade-of-Self-Reflection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Decade of Self Reflection" /><published>2020-06-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/Decade-of-Self-Reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/Decade-of-Self-Reflection/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/decadeofselfreflection.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Pixabay from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I gave titles to the decades of my life, my 30’s would be, “The Decade Of Self Reflection”. In my reflection, I have found my mindset to be my biggest set back. I have consistently been my own antagonist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-reflection&quot;&gt;My Reflection.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time and time again, I set myself up for complacency. I would talk myself out of action. I always had excuses for why I couldn’t do something. I never asked, “How can I do this?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some examples. I don’t have time. I don’t understand that. I’ll look into that. Other people will think its dumb. Sound familiar? These are the phrases we tell ourselves to stay lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I made it through these excuses, the possibility of failure set in. I would not allow myself to fail. Failure was not an option. Again, another defense mechanism to keep myself lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more and more I hear stories of successful people, I realize they do 2 things. First they ask themselves, “ What can I do?” Then they fail and learn from the mistakes. They take action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heres-what-happened-for-me&quot;&gt;Here’s what happened for me.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I changed my mindset from a statement to asking a question. Now I ask, “Why I can’t?”, instead of saying, “Why I can’t.” Notice they are the same set of words with different punctuation. Asking myself a question requires me to respond. A statement doesn’t. The statement shuts down the idea instantly. See how that works? Changing the punctuation, changes the mindset and the reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This small mindset change, changed the reflection and my reaction. In reality, I could’ve always done these things, but I was just too lazy to try. I was too busy making excuses instead of being busy trying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I just try most things and see what happens. I have tried so many things and failed. I have started blogs, tried video game streaming, Facebook groups, Reddit communities, Instagram accounts, and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From these failures, I have learned what my actual passions are and how to keep them fueled. Also, I have learned things that were unexpected such as marketing, forming communities, copy writing, and leveraging social media. I am still learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-mindset-is-your-reflection&quot;&gt;Your mindset is your reflection.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, I have learned that my mindset is the reflection I see. I am sure there is something that has been in the back of your mind that you want to accomplish. Ask yourself, “How can I do this?”. The answer that comes to mind, give it a try. I bet your reflection changes too. Before too long you will strike gold. I believe in you!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="/assets/postimg/decadeofselfreflection.jpeg" /><summary type="html">Photo by Pixabay from Pexels If I gave titles to the decades of my life, my 30’s would be, “The Decade Of Self Reflection”. In my reflection, I have found my mindset to be my biggest set back. I have consistently been my own antagonist. My Reflection. Time and time again, I set myself up for complacency. I would talk myself out of action. I always had excuses for why I couldn’t do something. I never asked, “How can I do this?” Here’s some examples. I don’t have time. I don’t understand that. I’ll look into that. Other people will think its dumb. Sound familiar? These are the phrases we tell ourselves to stay lazy. If I made it through these excuses, the possibility of failure set in. I would not allow myself to fail. Failure was not an option. Again, another defense mechanism to keep myself lazy. The more and more I hear stories of successful people, I realize they do 2 things. First they ask themselves, “ What can I do?” Then they fail and learn from the mistakes. They take action. Here’s what happened for me. I changed my mindset from a statement to asking a question. Now I ask, “Why I can’t?”, instead of saying, “Why I can’t.” Notice they are the same set of words with different punctuation. Asking myself a question requires me to respond. A statement doesn’t. The statement shuts down the idea instantly. See how that works? Changing the punctuation, changes the mindset and the reaction. This small mindset change, changed the reflection and my reaction. In reality, I could’ve always done these things, but I was just too lazy to try. I was too busy making excuses instead of being busy trying. Now I just try most things and see what happens. I have tried so many things and failed. I have started blogs, tried video game streaming, Facebook groups, Reddit communities, Instagram accounts, and businesses. From these failures, I have learned what my actual passions are and how to keep them fueled. Also, I have learned things that were unexpected such as marketing, forming communities, copy writing, and leveraging social media. I am still learning. Your mindset is your reflection. Most importantly, I have learned that my mindset is the reflection I see. I am sure there is something that has been in the back of your mind that you want to accomplish. Ask yourself, “How can I do this?”. The answer that comes to mind, give it a try. I bet your reflection changes too. Before too long you will strike gold. I believe in you!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I Hate The Person In The Mirror</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/article/I-Hate-The-Person-In-The-Mirror/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I Hate The Person In The Mirror" /><published>2020-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/article/I-Hate-The-Person-In-The-Mirror</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/article/I-Hate-The-Person-In-The-Mirror/">&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/maninthemirror.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Joseph Wayne Buchanan from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever heard the cliché, you are the people you surround yourself with? I know I sure have. In life, I have found by changing the people around me, I have changed the way of my life’s progression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been teaching my oldest son about choosing the people around him wisely. As I said before, he is starting high school this coming fall. He is at the age where kids are generally the most impressionable by their peers. In my life, I have noticed that most people don’t keep an eye on the people around them. My belief is this is what keeps people down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-influence-of-others&quot;&gt;The influence of others&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People can be easily influenced. Don’t believe me, take a look around your house. How many things do you see that are a name brand, you saw on TV, or social media? I’m not here to judge you. Currently, I am sitting in Nike clothes and Nike shoes. Why? “I wanna be like Mike.” Just kidding, but that is where it started for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a psychiatrist but I am guessing it starts as soon as we are born. Humans naturally learn by watching others. We start walking and talking because we see our parents doing it. Our culture learns from those people around us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These people can be broken into 3 different groups:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Friends and Family&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Community (Our peer group)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Influencers (Celebrities)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why your parents have probably said to you, “If so and so jumped over a bridge, would you do it too?” Unfortunately, in some aspects of our lives the answer is yes. This can be a good thing or a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-is-the-person-in-the-mirror&quot;&gt;Who is the person in the mirror?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is up to us to determine what is good and what is bad. In terms of our topic, it is up to us to determine what to mentality and influence to keep around. The people directly around us have the most influence and luckily, we control who we spend the most time with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the hard work, self reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you see yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you negative? Are you poor? Are you unhappy? Do you lack confidence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now look at the 5 people closest to you. Do you see any similarities? Most likely you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next decide what part of you, needs to change. Let’s say you want to be more positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now find at least one person in your peer group, who seems to be always positive. Start hanging with this person more than one other person in your group of 5. Now you need to spend less time with the most negative person in your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-beginning-of-change&quot;&gt;The Beginning of Change&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Letting someone go doesn’t mean you hate them, it just means you need better influence in your life. This doesn’t have to be permanent. You need someone with a different focus right now. You don’t have to stop talking to them. You might just need to stop talking to them so frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has that one negative person, let’s call them Negative Nancy (sorry Nancy it works for this example and you’re probably a really nice lady). When you talk to her, you find yourself hearing all the bad things in her world. Ultimately, you walk away feeling worse. To help you become more positive, you have to change the frequency of contact with Negative Nancy. This helps you stay positive more of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This applies to many other aspects of life. Continue to evaluate the closest 5 people to you. Want to be successful or work out more? Find a successful person or person that constantly works out. Start to hang out with these people more. You will slowly start to see your focus change. You will become more like the people you choose to be around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have done this subconsciously and consciously throughout my life (even accidentally). Every time, I have started to change those around me, I have major changes in my life. Emotionally it’s hard to do and takes a lot of self reflection and self awareness to complete.  In the end, you have to love yourself before you can love others. This is one small step to becoming a better you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><category term="mindset," /><category term="inner" /><category term="circle," /><category term="self" /><category term="reflection" /><summary type="html">Photo by Joseph Wayne Buchanan from Pexels Ever heard the cliché, you are the people you surround yourself with? I know I sure have. In life, I have found by changing the people around me, I have changed the way of my life’s progression. We have been teaching my oldest son about choosing the people around him wisely. As I said before, he is starting high school this coming fall. He is at the age where kids are generally the most impressionable by their peers. In my life, I have noticed that most people don’t keep an eye on the people around them. My belief is this is what keeps people down. The influence of others People can be easily influenced. Don’t believe me, take a look around your house. How many things do you see that are a name brand, you saw on TV, or social media? I’m not here to judge you. Currently, I am sitting in Nike clothes and Nike shoes. Why? “I wanna be like Mike.” Just kidding, but that is where it started for me. I am not a psychiatrist but I am guessing it starts as soon as we are born. Humans naturally learn by watching others. We start walking and talking because we see our parents doing it. Our culture learns from those people around us. These people can be broken into 3 different groups: Friends and Family Community (Our peer group) Influencers (Celebrities) This is why your parents have probably said to you, “If so and so jumped over a bridge, would you do it too?” Unfortunately, in some aspects of our lives the answer is yes. This can be a good thing or a bad thing. Who is the person in the mirror? It is up to us to determine what is good and what is bad. In terms of our topic, it is up to us to determine what to mentality and influence to keep around. The people directly around us have the most influence and luckily, we control who we spend the most time with. Now for the hard work, self reflection. How do you see yourself? Are you negative? Are you poor? Are you unhappy? Do you lack confidence? Now look at the 5 people closest to you. Do you see any similarities? Most likely you do. Next decide what part of you, needs to change. Let’s say you want to be more positive. Now find at least one person in your peer group, who seems to be always positive. Start hanging with this person more than one other person in your group of 5. Now you need to spend less time with the most negative person in your life. The Beginning of Change Letting someone go doesn’t mean you hate them, it just means you need better influence in your life. This doesn’t have to be permanent. You need someone with a different focus right now. You don’t have to stop talking to them. You might just need to stop talking to them so frequently. Everyone has that one negative person, let’s call them Negative Nancy (sorry Nancy it works for this example and you’re probably a really nice lady). When you talk to her, you find yourself hearing all the bad things in her world. Ultimately, you walk away feeling worse. To help you become more positive, you have to change the frequency of contact with Negative Nancy. This helps you stay positive more of the time. This applies to many other aspects of life. Continue to evaluate the closest 5 people to you. Want to be successful or work out more? Find a successful person or person that constantly works out. Start to hang out with these people more. You will slowly start to see your focus change. You will become more like the people you choose to be around. I have done this subconsciously and consciously throughout my life (even accidentally). Every time, I have started to change those around me, I have major changes in my life. Emotionally it’s hard to do and takes a lot of self reflection and self awareness to complete. In the end, you have to love yourself before you can love others. This is one small step to becoming a better you.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/maninthemirror.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/postimg/maninthemirror.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>