<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-26T14:10:50-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chad Underwood</title><subtitle>Personal site of Chad Underwood. Chad Underwood is a Systems Anaylst who specializes in Process Improvement.</subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020-07-01-My-Attitude-Needed-A-Wake-Up-Call/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2020-08-26T14:10:50-05:00</published><updated>2020-08-26T14:10:50-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020-07-01-My-Attitude-Needed-A-Wake-Up-Call</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020-07-01-My-Attitude-Needed-A-Wake-Up-Call/">&lt;p&gt;«««&amp;lt; HEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Attitude Needed A Wake Up Call
Photo by Andrew Neel from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/postimg/myattitudeneeded.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Attitude Needed A Wake Up Call&quot; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/@andrew?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels&quot;&gt;Andrew Neel&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/photo/man-wearing-black-crew-neck-shirt-and-black-jeans-3201765/?utm_content=attributionCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=pexels&quot;&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 6 a.m. The alarm goes off having to be out the door in 30 minutes to make it to work by 7 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hop out of bed. Run to start some coffee. Jump in the shower. Quickly brush my teeth. Sling on some clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running out the door, I pour the coffee into a travel cup and grab my wallet and keys. Now with no time to spare, zooming down the highway at 90 just hoping there’s no traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit the floor running with only seconds between being on time and being late. Starting everyday on a negative note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably would have a better attitude, by escaping my rush after waking up. There’s got to be a better way, I reflected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have come to believe, it is as easy as setting up a routine. So far, here is what I have found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 1. Prep the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you, like me, already know what you need for the next day. There’s no reason not to have it ready the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the same thing you need everyday. Clothes, a drink, some form of lunch, and a shower. Everything except maybe the shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 2. Wake up earlier&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is logical but it leads to the 3rd step. Waking up earlier would give time to gather thoughts and plan out the day. Then find a little peace before the chaos of the day starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just make sure not to procrastinate during this extra time. You will end up back where you started. Set a reminder and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3. Take time for yourself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I am not much of a morning person. Most people need coffee but I need isolation. I find that taking 30 minutes to start the day, I am much more productive and happy. This time gives me a chance to gather myself, my thoughts and prepare for the day ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How I am doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started to slowly incorporate these things into my day. I find that the days, that I do these things, I tend to be happier and more productive. The days where I skip one of these 3 things, the day is chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you can incorporate these into your routine and you will find similar results or maybe there is something you already do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;know-someone-who-would-benefit-share-with-a-friend-it-would-seriously-mean-the-world-to-me&quot;&gt;Know someone who would benefit? Share with a friend! (it would seriously mean the world to me)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-ideas-to-a-better-morning-routine&quot;&gt;3 Ideas To A Better Morning routine.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s 6 a.m. The alarm goes off having to be out the door in 30 minutes to make it to work by 7 a.m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hop out of bed. Run to start some coffee. Jump in the shower. Quickly brush my teeth. Sling on some clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running out the door, I pour the coffee into a travel cup and grab my wallet and keys. Now with no time to spare, zooming down the highway at 90 just hoping there’s no traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound familiar? &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/MyAttitudeNeededAWakeUpCall.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Worst Enemy&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Andrew Neel from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit the floor running with only seconds between being on time and being late. Starting everyday on a negative note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably would have a better attitude, by escaping my rush after waking up. There’s got to be a better way, I reflected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have come to believe, it is as easy as setting up a routine. So far, here is what I have found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-1-prep-the-night-before&quot;&gt;Step 1. Prep the night before.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you, like me, already know what you need for the next day. There’s no reason not to have it ready the night before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the same thing you need everyday. Clothes, a drink, some form of lunch, and a shower. Everything except maybe the shower.
Thibaut @Kpaxs
Your evening routine is about taking the decisions out of your morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to wake up already knowing what you’re going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2-wake-up-earlier&quot;&gt;Step 2. Wake up earlier&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is logical but it leads to the 3rd step. Waking up earlier would give time to gather thoughts and plan out the day. Then find a little peace before the chaos of the day starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just make sure not to procrastinate during this extra time. You will end up back where you started. Set a reminder and stick to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-3-take-time-for-yourself&quot;&gt;Step 3. Take time for yourself&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I am not much of a morning person. Most people need coffee but I need isolation. I find that taking 30 minutes to start the day, I am much more productive and happy. This time gives me a chance to gather myself, my thoughts and prepare for the day ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-i-am-doing&quot;&gt;How I am doing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started to slowly incorporate these things into my day. I find that the days, that I do these things, I tend to be happier and more productive. The days where I skip one of these 3 things, the day is chaotic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you can incorporate these into your routine and you will find similar results or maybe there is something you already do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;blockquote&gt;
          &lt;blockquote&gt;
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;08b8f06965af34c3f390f1ca035b1f3ea2d871f2&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;/blockquote&gt;
          &lt;/blockquote&gt;
        &lt;/blockquote&gt;
      &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s All My Fault</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Its-All-My-Fault/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It's All My Fault" /><published>2020-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Its-All-My-Fault</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Its-All-My-Fault/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-art-of-accountability&quot;&gt;The art of accountability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a manager that I would constantly butt heads with. He was military minded. I never seemed to have the right answer for him. I would explain to him endlessly. 
Truth be told, no one cared for him. All for the same reasons. Everyone said “He just doesn’t care to listen.” &lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/allmyfault.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;All My Fault&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Andrea Piacquadio from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-top-performer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Top Performer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time I was the top performer on our team and top 5% in our department. This is where you wanted to be in the rankings. He brought me into a meeting to let me know that I had a laundry list of things to improve on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After he was done, I was so angry with him that I really didn’t want to talk to him.  I ended up saying, “Yes sir, I’ll fix it.” The tension in the room instantly dropped on his side. I could tell I had made a stride on dealing with his unwillingness to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;explanations-are-just-another-excuse&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explanations are just another excuse&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I ended up learning about him would later, help me change my life. He didn’t want excuses. He took my explaining as excuses. He didn’t care, why it happened. He only wanted assurance, the problem would be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;controlling-the-situation&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controlling the situation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in life, I figured out this was called taking accountability. Taking accountability allows you to do 3 things. You stop arguments, blaming other people and control the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is being able to control your emotions. Emotions come from things, we feel, we can’t control. If you can stop the trigger of the emotions, you can move on quicker. Accountability is a sure fire way to control most of the emotions you feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-accountability-look-like&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What does accountability look like?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem:&lt;/strong&gt;  My kid made bad grades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The excuse:&lt;/strong&gt; They should’ve worked harder to get a better grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability:&lt;/strong&gt; I should’ve spent more time making sure they received the help they needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;heres-another-example&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s another example.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The problem:&lt;/strong&gt; My spouse doesn’t clean the house the way I like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The excuse:&lt;/strong&gt; My spouse is just lazy and half way does everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability:&lt;/strong&gt; I could’ve gotten up and helped to clean up the mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-part-of-the-problem&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be part of the problem.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see a pattern? Your excuses are what someone else could’ve done. The excuse could be 100% true. With accountability, you’ve got skin in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By taking accountability, you are now part of the problem. Being part of the problem, changes excuses into something you can control. Controlling the situation, gives you a freedom to fix any problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;out-of-control&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Out of control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somethings in life that you can’t control. For things you can’t control, learn to let them go. Learn to say, I can’t control this. After you say, “I can’t control it.”, move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You waste so much of your time on things you can’t control. You should take this wasted time and turn it into something productive. Instead invest this new energy into learning a hobby, side venture, or complete a goal you have been putting off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn to become accountable to everything around you. Then learn to let go of things you can’t control. You will find yourself in a much better place. You will have a clear head and a ton of time for you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="accountability," /><category term="excuses" /><summary type="html">The art of accountability I had a manager that I would constantly butt heads with. He was military minded. I never seemed to have the right answer for him. I would explain to him endlessly. Truth be told, no one cared for him. All for the same reasons. Everyone said “He just doesn’t care to listen.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Worst Enemy is Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/My-Worst-Enemy-is-Me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Worst Enemy is Me" /><published>2020-07-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/My-Worst-Enemy-is-Me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/My-Worst-Enemy-is-Me/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;small-changes-for-the-better&quot;&gt;Small changes for the better.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my life, I spent my quiet time coming up with ideas. Matter of fact, I have a ton of ideas. For those that know me well, I am a very analytical person.I analyze everything around me, constantly. When you meet me, I am very quiet. I am quiet because I am analyzing everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, I hold myself back from speaking. I do this because I don’t want to say something stupid. I lack confidence in social situations.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- _includes/image.html --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;image-wrapper&quot;&gt;
    
        &lt;img id=&quot;blog-image&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//assets/postimg/myworstenemyisme.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;My Worst Enemy&quot; /&gt;
    
    
        &lt;p class=&quot;image-caption&quot;&gt;Photo by Andrea Piacquadio from Pexels&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-great-procrastinator&quot;&gt;The Great Procrastinator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have one other thing that I hold myself back from, action. I tend to be a procrastinator. I always meet deadlines but scramble to get them done at the last minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend hours analyzing how to do something. I have to know everything before I can get started. I have found, what causes this procrastination for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;paralyzed&quot;&gt;Paralyzed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I feel like I know everything about a subject, then comes the what I need to get started. Here’s what those look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I need a new camera to start that YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I need more followers to start that newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I can’t post this on Instagram because its not a perfect picture.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What if someone doesn’t like it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The procrastination is not laziness. My procrastination is from fear of failure. This fear is paralyzing. Especially, for a person that lacks self confidence. I don’t want to be seen as a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comfortable-with-uncomfortable&quot;&gt;Comfortable with uncomfortable&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife on the other hand is super confident. I think that confidence is what draws me to her. We are the proverbial yin and yang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She drives me to want more from life. At first, I rejected this because it wasn’t normal to just do something that wasn’t planned out. Now, I have become somewhat comfortable with being uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stuck-on-the-diving-board&quot;&gt;Stuck on the diving board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much reflection here’s what I found. If I just start, the voices, in my head, have no influence over me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I wait until I feel ready, I never get started.  Here’s a good quote I came across from somewhere, “If you wait for the perfect temperature in the pool, you’ll always be left standing on the diving board.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read many biographies of, who I would deem, successful people. I have found these people all have the same trait. They start without knowing the how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful people, start and learn as they go. Then, they surround themselves with people who can teach them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-road-ahead&quot;&gt;The Road Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started to make myself do things. I’m still here. I’m not embarrassed. My failures are learning experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now fail in public more. You didn’t even see they happened. In the grand scheme of things, other people are not paying attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My self confidence is higher than ever. I’m moving forward and excited where this road will take me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you can find more confidence to start. Starting is the most important thing. Once you start, the rest falls in place. You’re not lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed this please tell your friends! (it would seriously mean the world to me)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="change," /><category term="procrastination," /><category term="confidence" /><summary type="html">Small changes for the better. Most of my life, I spent my quiet time coming up with ideas. Matter of fact, I have a ton of ideas. For those that know me well, I am a very analytical person.I analyze everything around me, constantly. When you meet me, I am very quiet. I am quiet because I am analyzing everything. Truth be told, I hold myself back from speaking. I do this because I don’t want to say something stupid. I lack confidence in social situations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Best feature of Twitter You’re Not Using</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/The-Best-feature-of-Twitter-You're-Not-Using/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Best feature of Twitter You're Not Using" /><published>2020-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/The-Best-feature-of-Twitter-You're-Not-Using</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/The-Best-feature-of-Twitter-You're-Not-Using/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-king-of-social-media&quot;&gt;The King of Social Media&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, I have sang the praises of Twitter. In my opinion, Twitter is the most powerful social network of all the land. It lends the best layout for conversation and networking with people you don’t know. The others are greared toward friends or people you know. &lt;!--more--&gt; They all have great features but for my money, Twitter is champion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-downside&quot;&gt;One Downside&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the site has grown, so have the issues. For one, the users of Twitter became very political. Politics are fine and in my opinion everyone should be able to share their thoughts any where they want. However, that doesn’t mean I actually want to hear them. There was a point all you would see and hear were people’s political opinions. It was so much for me in fact, I had to take a break from Twitter. I have seen others that have done the same. Twitter’s openness can also lead to burn out from an end user perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, during my hiatus, Twitter released an option to mute words. (From a quick search it looks like this released in 2016) This is the best feature that no other social network (to my knowledge) has caught on to. The ability to block keywords, or mute phrases brought me back to the network. It is a very simple featureand I have been a happy user since they implemented it and I was able to get mine setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You were able to block people for a long time. There are times when you don’t want to block someone because they may talk about other things you like to keep up with. This is where the mute words feature shines. Now you don’t have to see topics that you don’t care about and you can still follow anyone. It took a little while for me to get the right collection, but I have been able to configure Twitter to my liking. I no longer have to hear anybody’s political commentary or have my favorite shows and sporting events spoiled. Feature for feature this is the best setting of all of the social networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for the feature, head over to Settings&amp;gt;Privacy and Safety&amp;gt;Muted&amp;gt;Muted Words. You can get in here and start adding words, hashtags, or phrases. This setting as of 05/15/20 only seems to mute words in your main timeline. Maybe one day we will see a mute for the whole site. Then you can choose how long you want to mute the word or phrase and if you want to mute it from everyone or just people you don’t follow. After this you shouldn’t longer see the word/phrase&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="social" /><category term="networking," /><category term="twitter" /><summary type="html">The King of Social Media For years, I have sang the praises of Twitter. In my opinion, Twitter is the most powerful social network of all the land. It lends the best layout for conversation and networking with people you don’t know. The others are greared toward friends or people you know.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Best Friend, That Was There The Whole Time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/The-Best-Friend-That-Was-There-The-Whole-Time/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Best Friend, That Was There The Whole Time" /><published>2020-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/The-Best-Friend-That-Was-There-The-Whole-Time</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/The-Best-Friend-That-Was-There-The-Whole-Time/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;i-changed-my-default-search-engine-for-learning&quot;&gt;I changed my default search engine for learning.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over my years in tech, I’ve always said “Search engines are your best friend for learning new things.” This has always held true. I’ve started hanging with a new pal. &lt;!--more--&gt; 
I have found myself turning to YouTube for answers. In the past, search engines were king for everything. I have quit being old school and move to today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always knew there was a better place. But I habitually used web crawlers like Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bring-on-youtube&quot;&gt;Bring on YouTube&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube is best tool for learning. I am an audible learner. YouTube helps with my learning style. I can find someone who explains things in ways I understand best. Add visuals to the audio and there is no better tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YouTube has become a mature platform. You can find up any topic, you need or want to learn. There is no topic, I can’t find a how-to or a review for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a DIY’er or just don’t want to pay someone? YouTube should be your go to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the past few months I’ve learned:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;yard maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flower bed building&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;automated watering systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;photography&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;video editing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lawn mower repair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world of learning new things is at your beckoned call. You only have to remember YouTube is another resource. I have started to check YouTube before anything else. Using YouTube has saved my family a ton of time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always saw YouTube as a place for entertainment. I have found it to be way more than that. Lately, I have used YouTube countless times for more than just a laugh. Maybe, I am the only one. If not, I hope you will find yourself checking YouTube first.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="social" /><category term="media," /><category term="YouTube" /><summary type="html">I changed my default search engine for learning. Over my years in tech, I’ve always said “Search engines are your best friend for learning new things.” This has always held true. I’ve started hanging with a new pal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Create Rounded Corner Divs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Create-Rounded-Corner-Divs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Create Rounded Corner Divs" /><published>2020-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Create-Rounded-Corner-Divs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Create-Rounded-Corner-Divs/">&lt;p&gt;I created a launcher to link to certain things from my social media. This will allow me included links to multiple things from the bios in my social media. I started with squared corner divs and decided I wanted something that looked a little more like a button. I am sure this is something I will need to use in the future a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The border radius property in CSS is what allows you to round the corners on a square div. The lower, the number, the less round the corners are. The higher, the number, the more rounded the corners will get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only the border-radius property, in the example below, affects the roundness of the corners. This allow you to set the amount the corners will be rounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;example-code&quot;&gt;EXAMPLE CODE&lt;/h4&gt;
 	&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;style&amp;gt;
.example {  
width: 100px; 
height: 40px;
background-color: black;
border-radius: 15px; 
}
&amp;lt;/style&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;div id=&quot;example&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;output&quot;&gt;OUTPUT&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;example&quot; style=&quot;width: 100px; height: 40px; border-radius: 15px;background-color: black;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;  
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="divs," /><category term="css" /><summary type="html">I created a launcher to link to certain things from my social media. This will allow me included links to multiple things from the bios in my social media. I started with squared corner divs and decided I wanted something that looked a little more like a button. I am sure this is something I will need to use in the future a lot. The border radius property in CSS is what allows you to round the corners on a square div. The lower, the number, the less round the corners are. The higher, the number, the more rounded the corners will get. Only the border-radius property, in the example below, affects the roundness of the corners. This allow you to set the amount the corners will be rounded. EXAMPLE CODE &amp;lt;style&amp;gt; .example { width: 100px; height: 40px; background-color: black; border-radius: 15px; } &amp;lt;/style&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div id=&quot;example&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; OUTPUT</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How To Easily Generate Favicons</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Easily-Generate-Favicons/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Easily Generate Favicons" /><published>2020-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Easily-Generate-Favicons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-To-Easily-Generate-Favicons/">&lt;p&gt;Easy to generate Favicons for everything at once. I came across this website &lt;a href=&quot;https://realfavicongenerator.net/&quot;&gt;Real Favicon Generator&lt;/a&gt;. This allowed me to take my logo and upload it and then it did the lifting. I was prompted for some choices on how I wanted things to look. Next all I needed to do was click submit. Then I could download the results, which included a zip file of icons and the code to be input into the head of my site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="favicon," /><category term="logo," /><category term="html" /><summary type="html">Easy to generate Favicons for everything at once. I came across this website Real Favicon Generator. This allowed me to take my logo and upload it and then it did the lifting. I was prompted for some choices on how I wanted things to look. Next all I needed to do was click submit. Then I could download the results, which included a zip file of icons and the code to be input into the head of my site.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Off and On</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Off-And-On/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Off and On" /><published>2020-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Off-And-On</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Off-And-On/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-journey-in-tech&quot;&gt;My Journey in Tech&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This journey started in High School. I knew I was going to work in tech. Tech was the one passion I have always had, specifically computers. I had taken every single computer class I could. Then came my senior year and Advanced MIS. I always excelled in MIS. I passed everything with 100%. Then came my final assignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I had to do was build an application in VB (Visual basic for you young cats). I decided that I was going to make a black jack game. &lt;!--more--&gt; It seemed like it would use everything that we had learned in the class that year. We had 6 weeks to get it working. On the last day of the class, Chad’s version of Black Jack didn’t work. It was that day, I knew coding was not for me and I said I would never try again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have seen people post their personal portfolio websites and I knew I had to have one. I have wanted my own space where I fully owned my data. A site, unlike social media, where I control everything. The truth is I have had an idea of what I wanted my site to look like. I have searched to the end of the web and back to find a theme that would fit all the little details. So I decided to restart on my coding journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://freecodecamp.org&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;. Their site makes learning the basics of HTML and CSS easy. They walk you through learning bits and pieces at a time and it was easy for me. I was on the track to learning as quickly and as much as I could. Amazingly, one of the projects there is to create a personal portfolio site. I  was able to complete almost all of the content they were offering for a Front-End developer certificate. Then I was distracted by the blessing of a new child and life. So back off the track I went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-ahead&quot;&gt;Moving Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward, to this year (2020), we are once again expecting a new child. My wife has decided to go back to school and I needed something to fill my extra time. I still have the itch to create that personal website. I went back to freecodecamp.org and rushed through all of the tutorials once again to refresh. So now I am back on track and motivated more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What has made this time different than the others? I  found a great community on Twitter that motivates me. They are mostly experienced developers preaching the gospel of development. By preaching I mean, they let newer developers know the truth about development. They cut through the self depreciating thoughts, that you don’t know enough to be a compentent developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be known, I already knew this about tech; but failed to realize it about development. I always just assumed every developer knew most everything, about a language, before they started really doing development. Personally, I have been in the tech field for 13 years and I got my start by Googling everything. Now that I am more seasoned, I don’t have to Google as much but a search engine is my best friend. However, I found that a lot of the senior developers are just Googlers with experience; just like me. This made learning to code seem easier and obtainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-i-am-now&quot;&gt;Where I Am Now&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over these months, I have been working to take in little by litte. The difference, this time, has been knowing that I need to be steady and learn when I can. The fact, I don’t have to know everything just puts me at ease. Cramming has never been my strong suit because I tend to burn out fast (and it seems others do too)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past 3 months, I have been able to retain more than I ever have before and it all is just starting to make sense. In the past, things never seemed to connect. I could make things happen but nothing like now. I am actually releasing my site to the world and it is &lt;strong&gt;EXCITING!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a few projects lined out that should continue raise my confidence level. These projects will allow me to continue to learn new things but with deadlines involved, just like a developer would. It is exciting to know, this time, I stand a chance to make it! For those in #100daysofcode, you will make it too, if you stick with it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="myjourney," /><summary type="html">My Journey in Tech This journey started in High School. I knew I was going to work in tech. Tech was the one passion I have always had, specifically computers. I had taken every single computer class I could. Then came my senior year and Advanced MIS. I always excelled in MIS. I passed everything with 100%. Then came my final assignment. All I had to do was build an application in VB (Visual basic for you young cats). I decided that I was going to make a black jack game.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Manage Branches In GitHub</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-to-Manage-Branches-In-GitHub/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Manage Branches In GitHub" /><published>2020-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-to-Manage-Branches-In-GitHub</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-How-to-Manage-Branches-In-GitHub/">&lt;p&gt;I finally got to a point where I need to manage 2 sets of code for my personal website page. I created my Dev environment today so I can work on new features without taking a chance on destroying my currently working code. In theory, I understood why you run 2 code sets but now that I’ve seen the branches in action it makes more sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I had to do was create a second branch. This brought over my production code. From there all I needed to do was write new code and test it worked. Once I verified it was working, then I had to pull it into production. Easy, peasy!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="github," /><category term="branches" /><summary type="html">I finally got to a point where I need to manage 2 sets of code for my personal website page. I created my Dev environment today so I can work on new features without taking a chance on destroying my currently working code. In theory, I understood why you run 2 code sets but now that I’ve seen the branches in action it makes more sense. All I had to do was create a second branch. This brought over my production code. From there all I needed to do was write new code and test it worked. Once I verified it was working, then I had to pull it into production. Easy, peasy!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jekyll-Config-YAML</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-Jekyll-Config-yaml/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jekyll-Config-YAML" /><published>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-04-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-Jekyll-Config-yaml</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/til/TIL-Jekyll-Config-yaml/">&lt;p&gt;YAML is the configuration settings of a Jekyll site. You can setup custom fields to setup easy to change settings.This works great for things like social media names or things that are hard to remember but need to be referred to a lot.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll," /><summary type="html">YAML is the configuration settings of a Jekyll site. You can setup custom fields to setup easy to change settings.This works great for things like social media names or things that are hard to remember but need to be referred to a lot.</summary></entry></feed>